<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pedro Anastácio</title><link>https://pedroanastacio.com/</link><description>Recent content on Pedro Anastácio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pedroanastacio.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Time Management Is Really an Emotional Regulation Problem</title><link>https://pedroanastacio.com/posts/time-management-is-an-emotional-regulation-problem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pedroanastacio.com/posts/time-management-is-an-emotional-regulation-problem/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://pedroanastacio.com/posts/time-management-is-an-emotional-regulation-problem/images/time-management-emotional-problem.png" alt="Time Management Is Really an Emotional Regulation Problem"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-comfortable-lie-we-keep-repeating"&gt;The Comfortable Lie We Keep Repeating&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone has said, &amp;ldquo;I don’t have time&amp;rdquo;. I know I did. It&amp;rsquo;s the most socially acceptable lie we tell. It sounds reasonable. Responsible, even. And it&amp;rsquo;s kind of comfortable, as it suggests the problem is external — too many meetings, too many messages, too many demands. Not really my fault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when I look honestly at my days, that explanation collapses. I still have time to scroll, to switch between minor tasks. Time to stay busy just enough to feel productive.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SLC vs MVP: From Bare Minimums to Products Users Actually Love</title><link>https://pedroanastacio.com/posts/slc-vs-mvp-products-users-love/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pedroanastacio.com/posts/slc-vs-mvp-products-users-love/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://pedroanastacio.com/posts/slc-vs-mvp-products-users-love/images/meeting_new_product.png" alt="New Product Meeting"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more than a decade, &lt;em&gt;Minimum Viable Product&lt;/em&gt; has dominated how product teams think about new ideas. MVP became the default for startups, founders, and even internal innovation teams: build something tiny, ship it early, validate quickly, iterate relentlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On paper, it makes perfect sense. However, in practice&amp;hellip; we&amp;rsquo;ve stretched &amp;ldquo;minimum&amp;rdquo; to a breaking point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the way, MVP became an excuse to launch half-working demos disguised as products. Teams optimized for speed, not usefulness. Users got the short end of the stick — expected to test unfinished tools, provide feedback, and patiently wait while we &amp;ldquo;iterate.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The books that most impressed me in 2024</title><link>https://pedroanastacio.com/posts/2024-books/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pedroanastacio.com/posts/2024-books/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://pedroanastacio.com/posts/2024-books/images/book_glasses.jpg" alt="Empathic Leader"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite hobbies is reading, and in 2024, I reached a personal milestone: I read a record total of 26 books. While not all of them were lengthy epics—some were shorter novellas—each book offered something unique. My reading choices spanned across thrillers and science-fiction to insightful non-fiction, primarily focused on productivity and entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among all the books I read last year, two stood out: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Murderbot Diaries&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; in fiction (ok, this is a series, and I’m currently on volume five out of seven) and &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Working Backwards&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; in non-fiction.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Empathy is the New Strength in Leadership</title><link>https://pedroanastacio.com/posts/empathy-vs-strength/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pedroanastacio.com/posts/empathy-vs-strength/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://pedroanastacio.com/posts/empathy-vs-strength/images/empathic-leader.jpg" alt="Empathic Leader"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once seen as the foundation of good leadership, authority and technical skills are gradually being perceived as the tools of &amp;ldquo;old school leaders&amp;rdquo;. Technical expertise in an area of expertise is still imensly valuable, but on the other hand, authority is being replaced by empathy. Often dismissed as a mere soft skill, empahty is now redefining what it means to lead effectively in modern organizations. And it’s becoming essential.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Résumé</title><link>https://pedroanastacio.com/work/resume/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pedroanastacio.com/work/resume/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With over 20 years of experience across diverse industries such as telecommunications, banking, logistics, and healthcare, I have led high-impact projects, consistently delivering innovative, efficient, and scalable software solutions. I excel in team leadership, fostering collaboration and guiding cross-functional teams to meet complex business goals. Skilled at managing stakeholder relationships, I ensure alignment between technical and business objectives while driving projects to success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the founder of Nastech, I leverage my extensive expertise to design and implement cutting-edge technologies, combining creativity with a profound understanding of market needs to exceed client expectations. My passion for continuous learning and improvement fuels my commitment to delivering solutions that are both technically robust and strategically impactful.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title/><link>https://pedroanastacio.com/index-about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pedroanastacio.com/index-about/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="hi-there"&gt;Hi there!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my personal space, where you can get to &lt;a href="https://pedroanastacio.com/work/resume"&gt;know a bit more about me&lt;/a&gt; and what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll also share some of my thoughts about my passions, namely almost everything related with software engineering, productivity, politics and, who knows, maybe a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get in touch, please feel free to use my social links on this page!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>