<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pedro Anastácio</title><link>https://pedroanastacio.com/</link><description>Recent content on Pedro Anastácio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pedroanastacio.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Empathy is the New Strength in Leadership</title><link>https://pedroanastacio.com/posts/empathy-vs-strength/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pedroanastacio.com/posts/empathy-vs-strength/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://pedroanastacio.com/posts/empathy-vs-strength/images/empathic-leader.jpg" alt="Empathic Leader">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In today’s fast-paced and ever-changing world, leadership demands more than authority and technical prowess. Empathy, once dismissed as a mere soft skill, is now redefining what it means to lead effectively in modern organizations. As we navigate complex human dynamics, empathy is no longer optional; it’s essential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unlike skills that we learn and can apply mechanically, soft skills are usually connected to our emotional intelligence. There are numerous variables associated to soft skills, and one of those variables is what we perceive as our ability to be empathic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Résumé</title><link>https://pedroanastacio.com/work/resume/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pedroanastacio.com/work/resume/</guid><description>&lt;p>With over 20 years of experience across diverse industries such as telecommunications, banking, logistics, and healthcare, I have led high-impact projects, consistently delivering innovative, efficient, and scalable software solutions. I excel in team leadership, fostering collaboration and guiding cross-functional teams to meet complex business goals. Skilled at managing stakeholder relationships, I ensure alignment between technical and business objectives while driving projects to success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the founder of Nastech, I leverage my extensive expertise to design and implement cutting-edge technologies, combining creativity with a profound understanding of market needs to exceed client expectations. My passion for continuous learning and improvement fuels my commitment to delivering solutions that are both technically robust and strategically impactful.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://pedroanastacio.com/index-about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pedroanastacio.com/index-about/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="hi-there">Hi there!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Welcome to my personal space, where you can get to &lt;a href="https://pedroanastacio.com/work/resume">know a bit more about me&lt;/a> and what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll also share some of my thoughts about my passions, namely almost everything related with software engineering, productivity, politics and, who knows, maybe a bit more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to get in touch, please feel free to use my social links on this page!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>